Guide to the Edgar Eugene Robinson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Edgar Eugene Robinson papers
1880-1986
SC0029B
Robinson, Edgar Eugene, 1887-1977
66.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Edgar E. Robinson, 1966 and Mrs. Edgar E. Robinson, 1979, 1983, and 1991.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biography
Edgar E. Robinson was the Margaret Byrne Professor of History at Stanford University (1911-1952; emeritus, 1952-1977) and chairman of the History Department (1935-1952). He also served as Director of Independent Studies and of the Institute of American History. Especially well known for his work on American political parties, voting behavior, and presidential leadership, Professor Robinson played an integral role in the establishment of the Western Civilization course at Stanford.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, journals, newsclippings, drafts and manuscripts, lecture notes, syllabi, student term papers and administrative documents relating to Dr. Robinson's tenure as chairman of the History Department, his publications, work with the Commonwealth Club, and local defense activities during World War II.
Correspondents include E.D. Adams, Margery Bailey, Thomas A. Bailey, Edwin A. Cottrell, Ellwood P. Cubberley, Max Farrand, Albert Leon Guerard, David Harris, David Starr Jordan, George H. Knoles, Walter Lippman, Ralph H. Lutz, Alice M. Rose, Lewis M. Terman, Payson Jackson Treat, Frederick Jackson Turner, Ray Lyman Wilbur, John D. Works, and Yamato Ichihashi.
The collection also includes correspondence, photographs, and memorabilia of his first wife Katherine Young Robinson; and correspondence of his second wife Lisette Robinson.
The University Archives also has seven reel-to-reel tapes of Professor Robinson's memoirs and the taped readings about Herbert Hoover from his journal which are housed with the Archives' tape collection.
Access Terms
Adams, Ephraim Douglass, 1865-1930.; Bailey, Margery, 1891-1963; Bailey, Thomas Andrew, 1902-1983.; Cottrell, Edwin A.; Cubberley, Ellwood Patterson, 1868-1941; Farrand, Max, 1869-1945.; Guérard, Albert Léon, 1880-1959.; Harris, David,, 1900-; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Ichihashi, Yamato.; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931; Knoles, George Harmon.; Lippman, Walter.; Lutz, Ralph Haswell, 1886-1968.; Robinson, Edgar Eugene, 1887-1977; Robinson, Katherine Young.; Robinson, Lisette.; Rose, Alice M.; Stanford University. Department of History. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Stanford University. Independent Studies Program.; Stanford University. Institute of American History; Terman, Frederick Emmons, 1900-1982; Treat, Payson J. (Payson Jackson), 1879-1972; Turner, Frederick Jackson, 1861-1932.; Wilbur, Ray L., (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949; Works, John D. (John Downey), 1847-1928; History--Research.; Notes.; Photoprints.; Syllabi.
Collection Contents
- Professional Correspondence Files, 1910-1952
  - 1910 - 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Letters regarding E.E. Robinson's coming to Stanford U. (Adams, Jordan).
  - 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    From Munroe Smith.
    Robinson to F.J. Turner.
    Mrs. Wm. Kittle about Progressive Movement.
    Mss. of book review.
  - 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Correspondence with Adams, especially concerning Robinson's employment.
    Correspondence with Alvin S. Johnson, especially concerning Robinson's study of the 1912 Presidential election for the Political Science Quarterly and with reference to Robinson's past career and present work.
    Franklin Jameson - maps, letter to Adams re: confusion in planning of courses.
  - 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Letters to E.D. Adams, H.E. Bolton, from Carl R. Rich (?).
    Letters from Alvin S. Johnson.
  - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    E.D. Adams - Dept. news; letters from P.A. Martin, P.J. Treat (incl. political problems), Alvin S. Johnson; to Guy S. Ford (Minnesota), offer by Ford Norris Gage; review of Sectional Significance of the Public Lands by R.G. Wellington; from Solon J. Buck, George Charles, E.D. Adams.
  - 1916 - 1919 (mostly 1916) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Letters from J. H. Morse, John W. Kern, John M. McBride & crisis for Sewanee review; Philippine fear of Japan; to George Patton (Senate candidate); to Hubert Croly (election results); from H. Croly (editor of New republic); to John Bender (politics); E.D. Adams (Dept. business); letter to Edward A. White (concerning brother Stephen's ms. material); Daniel C. Roper (re Robinson's statistical work for Democratic National Committee); Payson J. Treat; several letters regarding national election of 1916; Norris L. Gage (sec'y. to Sen. Stewart of Nevada); letter to Wilbur recommending H.H. Sayre for ambulance driving; state librarian (re ms. of ex-Sen. Booth); E.D. Adams (re war issues course); R.S. Gray (especially re current situation); correspondence re Yale appointment; The California Idea.
  - 1917 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    E.B. Krehbiel; William Kettner (re Horace M. Conard); Agreement with Macmillan Co. (re The Foreign Policy of Woodrow Wilson); A.C. Krey; George W. Marston (files of San Diego Union); National Board for Historical Service (re a war aims course & historians' service during war); National Security League (patriotism through education, speaking engagement); C.D. Carus (re draft, enlistments, pacifists, etc.); John R. Casserly, Phoenix High School speaking engagement; summary of year's work; Letter to John D. Works seeking interview; Jeanne Wiel (re Sen. Stewart materials); more John D. Works; George B. Willcutt (re J.L. Willcutt); to R.L. Wilbur (need to disseminate information on events leading up to current war situation); Daniel C. Roper (Democratic National Committee - analysis of 1916 vote); Committee on Occupational Selection; National Security League: outline of plan for public addresses and lectures; Joseph L. Pease (S.T. Gage ms.); J.D. Spreckels; State Council of Defense for California; to F.J. Turner (National Board for Historical Service); William Trimble; Robert L. Coleman; A.H. Fulton (re lectures for Phoenix High School); Carl R. Fish (especially re The Foreign Policy of Woodrow Wilson and affairs of the National Board for Historical Service); Alvin Johnson; H.E. Huntington.
    Norris Gage (re Stewart & C.P.)
  - 1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    E. Krehbiel; P.G. Miller (especially re Clayton D. Carus); C.D. Carus; Comments on current history in letter to J. Earl B___ (?); Daniel C. Roper (election publicity); Victor J. West (includes comments on domestic, foreign political situation); J.T. Shotwell; F.J. Turner (especially re informing the public about current history); C.R. Fish; Camp Fremont; history lectures; Geo. C. Hodges (of Wash. State College; comments on Ichihashi).
  - 1919 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    William Kittle (concerning candidacy for presidency of U. of New Mexico); E. Krehbiel (includes comments on political situation by E.K.); P.A. Martin; F.L. Payson (recommending Robinson); George E. Crothers; speaking engagement for League to Enforce Peace; J. Earl Baker; Commonwealth Club of Calif.; Daniel C. Roper; letter to H.C. Hoover (concerning records of Stanford people in World War I); U.S. Food Administration; letter to R.L. Wilbur (re leadership of U.S.; Walter Rathenau); John E. Bennett (re The Great Cycle); Everett Colby; Victor J. West; Henry Suzzallo; 1854 Indian (Omaha) affairs (letter to A.B. Snow); Max Farrand (requests Robinson to take his place temporarily); R.S. Gray (Commonwealth Club of Calif. - interest in League Nations); National Institution for Moral Instruction Inc.; C.R. Fish; J.E. [Baker] (?) (comments on current position of Japanese, especially in China); F.J. Turner; P.J. Treat (Stanford enrollment, Dept. news, introduction of tuition, other news); Charles Hodges; Alvin S. Johnson (re Wilson & Roosevelt); Max Farrand.
  - 1920 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    E. Krehbiel; H.E. Bolton; Frank M. Russell; Victor J. West; R.L. Wilbur (Robinson's comments on contemporary civilization & national politics); Max Farrand; comments on Gov. Cox of Ohio by (?); E.D. Adams (including extensive comments on re-organization of undergraduate instruction); Hoover Collection; F.L. Payson; D.S. Jordan.
  - 1921 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Ralph H. Gabriel; Edward M. Hulme; Geo. C. Hodges; correspondence with publishers; Christian A. Herter; Walter M. Hart; Victor J. West (includes comments on citizenship course); R.L. Wilbur (Hoover archives, Stanford War History); Silver, Burdett & Co. (Robinson's American History); William A. Dodd (re Woodrow Wilson); correspondence regarding reed College; History Club; Max Farrand; Richard F. Scholz; H.E. Bolton; Everett S. Brown; Commonwealth Club of Calif.; J. Earle Baker (especially re Chinese famine); P.J. Treat (?) (experiences in the Far East); M. Anesaki; E.D. Adams (re Robinson's work in Wash. D.C. for Hoover Institute); letters Walter Lippmann; H.B. Learned; E. Krehbiel; Ralph Lutz; Douglas MacArthur; William E. Dodd; P.J. Treat (experiences in Japan); Korekujo Takahashi; Colonial Dames of America (Sulgrave Manor, England); comments on American & British political systems in letter Donald R. Richberg; notices concerning purchase of on-campus homes by faculty members; Mabel E. Simpson; letter to F.J. Turner (re Jacksonian politics)
  - 1922 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    William E. Dodd; Washington Conference; Silver, Burdett & Co.; various speaking engagements; letters to P.J. Treat (largely concerned with Far Eastern affairs); Alden H. Abbott; materials from Washington Conference on Armament Limitation for Hoover Collection; Walter Lippmann; 1922 Indiana Senate primary; Committee on the Summer Quarter; G. Charles Hodges; letter to Bernard Baruch (chiefly national politics); Ruth Bartlett (teaching at Humboldt State); George Herron (comments on near-East and Italian political situation); Richard F. Scholz (wants Robinson at reed); book reviews.
  - (Part I), 1923 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Charles Gardner (national repentence); Ralph H. Gabriel; Eldon Griffin; recommendation of T.A. Bailey (to F.P. Griffiths); R.G. Gettell; minutes History Club of the California Academy of Social Sciences; History of the United States by Thwaites and Kendall (correspondence with Houghton Mifflin Co.); R.L. Wilbur (re Robinson's attendance at professional meetings, promotion to full professor); Robinson speeches (4th of July, attacking biased texts); information for president's report; American creed and people; acquisition of congressional record (Samuel Shortridge); school of Social Sciences; Stephen M. White papers (in letter to G.T. Clark); Wisconsin class of 1908 reunion; George Clarence (?); T.J. Norton; National Economic League; Stockton 4th of July celebration; AHA Pacific Coast branch (letter to Wilbur); comments re certain textbooks; Allen M. Kline (re John G. Howes); Time magazine; Harlow Lindley; National Council for Prevention of War; William Kittle; California League of Women Voters; letter to F.J. Turner (re library, Hoover Collection, History Dept.); American review; C.D. Tenney (?) (moral conditions in China); California Academy of Social Sciences; Ford M. Tussing (poor scholastic performace of men engaged in extra-curricular activity); speaking engagements; Lou Henry Hoover (essay contest); Herbert C. Jones; D.S. Jordan.
  - (Part II), 1923 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    American Political Parties (Harcourt, Brace & Co.); Charles E. Martin (education in social studies); Owen C. Cox; AHA Pacific Coast branch; Charles E. Martin; pyschology & politics; Commonwealth Club of California (international relations); letter to F.J. Turner; Robert G. Cleland; California State Historical Association; L.J. Paetow; Iron Cross; materials concerning T.A. Bailey's application for Rhodes Scholarship; William E. Boran; E.H. Basnor; Edgar J. Banks; data for president's report; Charles Hodges; John G. Howes.
  - (Part I), 1924 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Ralph H. Gabriel (re Gabriel's book); Carl R. Fish; Max Farrand (report on Gazeway Courses in history); R.L. Wilbur; L.E. Fast; Census of college staffs by American Council on Education; J. Earle Baker (Chinese economics & politics); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; National Council for Prevention of War (wanting contributions); Walter Lippmann, Sarah A. Young; Norman V. Donaldson; R.L. Wilbur; League of Nations Non-Partisan Association; Citizenship course; speaking engagements; speakers for spring quarter; address on Washington & Lincoln (Memorial Church, 24 Feb. 1924); comments on 1924 campaign & Coolidge in letters to Daniel C. Roper & W.A. Robinson; summary of work done in past year; impressions of various campuses; Professor Edgar E. Robinson at 21 years of age (includes comments on interview with W.J. Bryan); summer Oxford instruction for Americans; conference with Bd. of Trustees regarding purpose & content of courses; referendum to the National Council of the National Economic League on the World Court; comments on citizenship course in letter to J. Earle Baker; Angelina Burns; recommendation of T.A. Bailey for Rhodes Scholarship.
  - (Part II), 1924 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Brochure on Peking Univ.; job offer by Leigh Univ.; appointment as U.C. lecturer; summer offer from Utah Agricultural College; M. Panunzio; W. Lippmann (comments on Robinson's book on political parties); essay contest for women sponsored by Mrs. Hoover; death of Richard Scholz; F.J. Turner retirment dinner; Paul H. Clyde; E.D. Adams; Angelina Burns; Roberta Thompson; Colonial Grand Dames of America (essay contest won by David Harris); recommendation of D. Harris for Rhodes Scholarship; Robinson's publishers; J.G. Maytin; speaking engagements; Joseph M. Clyde; Sir Francis Drake Association; Margaret E. Bennett; Samuel Shortridge (Senate & House calendars); E.O. Sisson; E.P. Cubberley (required constitution course); E.R. Colburn (Mexican democracy).
  - (Part I), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Lewis M. Terman; letter to F.J. Turner asking him to lecture; Max Farrand; recommendations of Edith Dobie; Mary W. Williams (re E. Dobie & women Ph.D. in general); H.E. Bolton (re E. Dobie, T.A. Bailey); The White Papers & Miss Dobie's Thesis; Norman Coleman; The Washington Conference - extracts from letters from Wash. D.C.; American Council on Education Placement Service; Merle Alderman; E.D. Adams Dixon Ryan Fox; Max Farrand; Carl R. Fish; letter Chester A. Rowell soliciting for AHA; William Kittle; Robert Littler; League of Nations Non-Part san Association; E.O. Sisson - moral education; F.J. Turner; Colonial Dames of America; San Francisco Chamber of Commerce banquet; concern over Japanese situation; recommendation of Paul H. Clyde; H. Croly (of The New republic); citizenship instructors' conference - 23 Apr. 1925; Nobel Peace Prize announcement & recommendation of D.S. Jordan for prize; Harcourt, Brace & Co.; first Calif. gasoline-driven automobile; C.F. Huth Jr.; Charles Hodges; Allen Johnson; W. Westergaard; Own C. Coy (re funds for Calif. State Historical Association); letter to H. Jones (same topic); H.C. Hockett; John G. Howes.
  - (Part II), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Sartell Prentice; E.O. Sisson, deportation of John C. Schadel (Dept. of Labor to D.S. Jordan); Mary A. Moore (slave labor in Calif. mines?); Phi Beta Kappa (Richard H. Piatt, R.L. Wilbur); C.[W.] Panunzio; information for president's report; Max Farrand; William A. Robinson; Charles B. Kuhlman; graduate students; League of Nations Non-Partisan Association; The Trend of Naval Affairs (R.E. Krause); use of Yale Univ. Press films for history classes; speech; R.L. Wilbur (citizenship course); Mrs. G.T. Gerlinger (considering Robinson for U. of Oregon presidency); AHA Pacific Coast branch; Eugene I. McCormac; F.E. Morgan; Paul H. Douglas; use of Yale Univ. Press films (motion pictures) in classroom; efforts of The American Foundation to Further Progress in Senate of the World Court; Mary Williams; E.D. Adams (re Fort Sumter); academic freedom & academic tenure; T.A. Bailey; Hayes Baker-Crothers Edgar Lee Masters (re W.J. Bryan); Carl R. Fish; reference to Levi Stowell diary in correspondence with Mrs. M.E. Emery; Yale Univ. Press (ms. of California [by Farrand?]); H.E. Bolton (re T.A. Bailey); Frederick Merk (re Bailey); E.O. Sisson; Angelina Burns; C.M. Panunzio.
  - (Part I), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Work in the History of the West at Stanford; Squires materials; Phi Beta Kappa; W. Mayo Newhall; correspondence concerning Robinson & presidency of Univ. of Oregon; C.H. Van Tyne; R.L. Wilbur; war record of Stanford men & women; Samuel Shortridge; T.A. Bailey & letters to & from C.R. Fish & H.E. Bolton concerning Bailey.
  - (Part II), 1926 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    American Peace Society (invitation to join); Max Farrand; Colonial Dames essay contest & scholarship; Frank P. Deering; publication of Edith Dobie's thesis; problems of citizenship - sectioning classes according to ability; Henry B. Learned; The American Foundation (re World Court resolution); Edgar Kiess; application (for European travel) to the Kahn Foundation for the foreign travel of American teachers (including copies of recommendations by Farrand, Jordan, G. Showerman; F.J. Turner, Wilbur); Victor J. West; Thomas A. Bailey; Charles Hodges (including travel offer to Hodges from Carnegie Endowment for International Peace); J. Hugh Jackson; E.G. Mears (race & trade in citizenship course).
  - (Part I), 1927 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    F.L. Paxson; Edith Dobie; L. Fast (extensive correspondence); William Kittle; death of Victor J. West; O.H. Wedel; R.L. Wilbur; T.A. Bailey; speaking engagements; J. Earle Baker; T.D. Boardman; H.E. Bolton; J. Hugh Jackson.
  - (Part II), 1927 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    World Federation of Education Associations; P.J. Treat; Charles M. Swain, Clark E. Persinger (Sen. Stewart papers); Social Science research Council (inquiry concerning methods in selected research projects); William A. Robinson; E.D. Adams; American Legislators' Association annual meeting; Henry S. Anderson, J.E. Wier (re confiscation of Nevada State Historical Society papers by a political board); W. Westergaard; G.T. Clark; W. Henry Cooke.
  - (Part I), 1928 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    James R. Cutting, Edith Dobie; Edwin Deller; Herbert Croly (re Robinson's objections to The New republic's support for Gov. Smith as president); J.W. Fesler; L. Fast; Max Farrand; Virginia E. Fox (re diary of Capt. Bouldin); Ralph Lutz; Mrs. Wm. Kent; Colonial Dames of America; A.C. Krey; Donald Barnes recommendations of N.C. Belk to other institutions; letter to Robinson's grandfather; J.E. Baker; L.L. Bernard (encyclopedia of social sciences); H.E. Bolton; Thomas S. Barclay (includes comments on national politics, especially re Smith & Hoover); T. Bailey; Russell Buchanen; letter to Wm. H. Henry of Socialist Party; Frances I. Hus; letter to John P. Irish Jr. re Stephen M. White letter; recommendation of David Harris to Univ. of South Carolina; D.S. Jordan; H.C. Hockett; David Harris; H.P. Mack; L.A. Mander, Merk; B. McAnear; radio speech for National League of Women Voters; Milton Conover.
  - (Part II), 1928 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Bernice Tompkins; W.W. Insley; returns on presidential elections in Nevada & Calif.; papers of Nevada Historical Society; B.F. Shambaugh (John P. Irish papers); Robinson's expression of political support for Hoover in letter to R.N. Shott; [J. Shannon]; letter to G.F. Parker (seeking information on J.P. Irish material); W.A. Robinson; Wm. H. Ellison; Mrs. W.E. Junkert; AHA Pacific Coast branch; Franklin C. Palm; Frank W. Pitman; Owen C. Coy; L.J. Paetow; J.C. Parish; James R. Cutting; New York Telegram (Robinson's prediction of election results); summer session at Univ. of Oregon; The American Foundation (advocating American participation in the World Court); American Civil Liberties Union (unfair treatment of Chinese); Preston B. Albright; Henrik C. Andersen (correspondence with Jordan re International City); speaking engagements; Edward White; Jeanne E. Wier (Stewart papers); Ruth E. Wright; T.J. Walsh for President; request to Wilbur by Robinson that he not be reappointed director of Citizenship; letter to The New republic disagreeing with their support of Smith for President; Albert F. Coyle; D.E. Clark.
    [Note: No Folder #25]
  - (Part I), 1929 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Edith Dobie; C.A. Duniway, diary of James G. Bell; Max Farrand; correspondence re B. McAnear; Seba Elridge; Dudley H. Burney; Ralph Gabriel; F.G. Guittard; Robert J. Kerner (dinner with U.C. History Dept.); A.C. Krey; Florence P. Kahn (request for census map); R.B. von Kleinsmid (especially re Y. Ichihashi); Ralph Lutz (re E.D. Adams); Lottie Woods (Colonial Dames of America scholarship & essay contest): educational radio; reginald Bell; H.M. Bacon; J.E. Baker; H.W. Bradley; T.A. Bailey; O.S. Johnson; Institute of Statesmanship; D.S. Jordan; Charles Hodges; David Hazen; Dictionary of American Biography; David Harris (complains about conditions at Univ. of South Carolina); Victor H. Harding; Walter J. Hall; C.W. Hackett; Marnie Jackson; B. McAnear; G.H. Marx; M. Murphy; P.A. Martin; E.A. Cottrell.
  - (Part II), 1929 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    P.J. Treat (John F. Swift papers): Department Sandards; report of meeting of School of Social Sciences; James W. Thompson; Nathan Van Patten; Samuel Shortridge; John C. Parish; Frank C. Palm; C. Panunzio; C.A. Paullin (Library of Congress); Alfred Powers (Univ. of Oregon summer school); F.A. Rice; Royal Historical Society; S.K. Ratcliff; O.O. Winther; O.H. Wedel; M.S. Wildman (faculty research); H. Cooke; J.J. Coss (Columbia Univ. contemporary civilization course); Modern Methods of Warfare & Protection of the Civilian Population (Conference in Frankfurt); W. Westergaard; John R. Nichols; fellowships; Preston B. Albright; The American Foundation (World Court Problem); Paul H. Clyde (travels in Japan, Korea, China); Colonial Dames of America.
  - 1930 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Edith Dobie; H.H. Fisher; Carl R. Fish; to Max Farrand (concerning letters in Huntington Library); Charles Gardner; Univ. of Oregon (vacancy in History Dept.); Albert Guerard; A.C. Krey; changes in Dept. (letter to H.B. Learned): F.C. Wooton; Harold W. Bradley; Anne Bancroft; M.P. Briggs; L.E. Bassett; Lottie G. Woods (Colonial Dame of America); W. Westergaard; Frank J. Klingberg; speaking engagements; Commonwealth Club of California; E.A. Cottrell (Social Science research Council); T.A. Bailey; T.S. Barclay; R. Buchanan; H.B. Bard; R. Swain; David Hazen; E.L. Harvey; David Harris (work in England): V.H. Harding; to Mrs. T.J. Hoover; F.H. Hodder; Marie Jackson; to Mrs. Jordan; P.A. Martin; B. McAnear.
  - (A - Al), 1930 - 1935 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    H.M. Adams; Committee for the Immediate Defense of Constitutional Rights; auditing of classes; W.F. Adams; E.D. Adams; Florence Adams; American Civil Liberties Union; R.E. Albright (includes dissertation abstract); 1934 Alumni Conference; effect of depression on AHA (J. G. de Roulhal Hamilton); Jane E. Adams.
  - ( American Democracy in Times of Crisis), 1930 - 1935 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    R.L. Wilbur; D. Charles Gardner; W.T. Root; G.S. Ford; Ralph H. Gabriel; Henry Lanz; Dorothea Wyatt.
  - (American Historical Association), 1932 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    C. Martin; Toronto meeting; C.A. Beard; memorandum on arrangements for publication of the report of the Commission on the Social Studies; R. Gabriel (Program Committee); R.C. Clark; Edith Dobie; T.A. Bailey; report of the Committee of the AHA on the planning of research; AHA analysis of programmes of meetings; Dexter Perkins (re American Historical review); 1931 AHA meeting.